The first thing you need to do when
integrating Torus to Canvas is to ensure
cue-2
that OLI Torus is registered as an LTI
Advantage Tool in your institution's
cue-3
Canvas system. This is typically handled
by a Canvas administrator. If your Canvas
cue-4
admin hasn't integrated OLI Torus yet,
contact OLI support at
cue-5
oli-help@cmu.edu.
cue-6
Okay, now to place the OLI Torus link to
Canvas, you have three options, the
cue-7
navigation menu, an assignment, or a
module. Adding OLI Torus to the navigation
cue-8
menu is recommended if you and students
need to enter it frequently. This will
cue-9
result in OLI Torus also being visible on
the Canvas class homepage. Adding OLI
cue-10
as an assignment is the recommended
placement. This allows you to place OLI in
cue-11
your weekly curriculum and assign the
reading as homework or out-of-class
cue-12
activities. Adding OLI Torus as a module
will allow students to navigate to OLI
cue-13
through the module view. To avoid
confusion, add your Torus course link in
cue-14
only one place, navigation menu,
assignments, or modules.
cue-15
Option one, add the link to the navigation
menu. Go to Settings at the bottom of the
cue-16
Canvas navigation menu, click the
Navigation tab on the top, and scroll to
cue-17
find OLI Torus, not the other ones under
Disabled Items. Drag it up to the list of
cue-18
enabled navigation items and click Save.
OLI Torus will now appear in your course's
cue-19
left-hand menu. Option two, add the link
in an assignment.
cue-20
Click Assignments, Add Assignment, and add
a title. This is what students will see
cue-21
when they click on Assignments in the
Canvas class. Scroll down to Submission
cue-22
Type, select External Tool, click Find,
cue-23
choose OLI Torus from the list, and click
Load in a New Tab. Click Save and
cue-24
Publish or Save. If necessary, publish the
OLI Torus assignment by clicking the Not
cue-25
Published icon on the right side of the
page. Option three, add the link in a
cue-26
module. Click Modules in the nav menu.
Then create a new module. Give the module
cue-27
a name such as OLI Torus Course, or base
the title on your Torus content, and click
cue-28
Add Module.
cue-29
In the new module, click the plus sign and
select External Tool.
cue-30
Select OLI Torus from the list, update the
title if you like, click Load in a New
cue-31
Tab, and click Add Item.
cue-32
Publish the OLI Torus module by clicking
the Unpublished icon on the right end of
cue-33
the OLI Torus module. And once you've
added the link to Canvas, it's time to
cue-34
configure your OLI Torus course materials
for use with your students. Click the OLI
cue-35
Torus link you just added to load it in a
new tab and configure your OLI Torus
cue-36
materials. Click Start and follow the
prompts. Select a source material to base
cue-37
your course on. Use the search feature to
find the desired content if necessary. Now
cue-38
enter basic info link, course name,
course section number, can be a catalog
cue-39
number or CRN, for example, and modality
for how class meets
cue-40
and other course details.
cue-41
Voila, your section has now been created.
cue-42
Note that once set up, all links will
point to the same OLI Torus course no
cue-43
matter where students access it from in
Canvas. Students have no OLI Torus
cue-44
accounts. They will access everything from
the Canvas link. There you have it. In
cue-45
just a few steps, you can add and
configure OLI Torus in your Canvas course.
cue-46
If you need to unlink a course, contact
OLI support at
cue-47
oli-help@cmu.edu.